Lesson 19 The stuff of dreams
话梦话的本质
First listen and then answer the following question.
听录音,回答以下问题.
What is going on when a person experiences rapid eye-movements during sleep?
当一个人在睡眠中突然有眼部活动时,什么事情正在发生?
It is fairly clear that the sleeping period must have some function,
很清楚,睡眠必然具有某种作用.
and because there is so much of it the function would seem to be important.
睡眠占去那么多时间,所以其作用似乎还很重要.
Speculations about its nature have been going on for literally thousands of years,
人们对睡眠作用的种种猜测,确实已有数千年之久.
and one odd finding that makes the problem puzzling
一项使人对这个问题感到困惑的奇怪的,
is that it looks very much as if sleeping is not simply a matter of giving the body a rest.
发现是,睡眠在很大程度似乎并不仅仅是为了使身体得到休息.
'Rest',in terms of muscle relaxation and so on,
"休息",从使肌肉得到放松等方面来看,
can be achieved by a brief period lying,or even sitting down.
只要稍微躺一躺,甚至坐一坐就能达到.
tissue: n.  组织
The body's tissues are self-repairing and self-restoring to a degree,
人体组织在一定程度上有自我修补和自我恢复的能力,
and function best when more or less continuously active.
有张有弛地连续活动时,其功能最佳.
In fact a basic amount of movement occurs during sleep
事实上,睡眠状态下仍有着基本的活动量,
which is specifically concerned with preventing muscle inactivity.
以防止肌肉活动停止.
If it is not a question of resting the body,
如果睡眠的功能不是在于使身体得到休息,
then perhaps it is the brain that needs resting?
那么也许是让大脑得以休息?
hypothesis: n.  假说
This might be a plausible hypothesis were it not for two factors.
若不是下面两点,这种假设似乎是有道理的.
electroencephalograph: n.  脑电图仪
First the electroencephalograph,
第一点,脑电图记录仪，
which is simply a device for recording the electrical activity of the brain
(不过是一种记录脑电活动的仪器）
electrode: n.  电极, scalp: n.  头皮
by attaching electrodes to the scalp)
方法是通过把电极接到头皮上来记录.)
shows that while there is a change in the pattern of activity during sleep,
显示人在睡眠时大脑活动的方式有变化,
there is no evidence that the total amount of activity is any less.
但没有迹象表明,其活动总量有任何减少.
The second factor is more interesting and more fundamental.
第二点更有意思,也更重要.
psychiatrist: n.  精神病学家
Some years ago an American psychiatrist named William Dement published experiments,
前些年,美国一位名叫威廉.迪蒙特的精神病学者发表了一个报告,
dealing with the recording of eye-movements during sleep.
报告中记录了眼球在睡眠时的活动情况.
He showed that the average individual's sleep cycle
他指出,平常人的睡眠周期中
punctuate: v.  不时介入
is punctuated with peculiar bursts of eye-movements,
不时伴有一阵阵奇怪的眼球活动,
some drifting and slow,others jerky and rapid.
这些活动有的飘忽而缓慢,有的急剧而快速.
People woken during these periods of eye-movements,
在眼球活动期间被叫醒的人，
generally reported that they had been dreaming.
都说自己在做梦;
When woken at other times they reported no dreams.
在其他期间叫醒他们,则说没做梦.
If one group of people,
如果有一组人，
were disturbed from their eye-movement sleep for several nights on end,
连续几夜在眼球活动时被叫醒,
and another group were disturbed for an equal period of time
另一组人也是连续几夜被叫醒,
but when they were not exhibiting eye-movements,
但是在眼球没活动时被叫醒的,
disorder: n.  失调
the first group began to show some personality disorders
结果,第一组人开始出现性格失常,
while the others seemed more or less unaffected.
而第二组人似乎没受什么影响.
implication: n.  表明
The implications of all this were that
这一切暗示我们:
it was not the disturbance of sleep that mattered,
睡眠受到干扰没关系,
but the disturbance of dreaming.
而做梦受到干扰是有问题的.